BRUCE BELCHER

Chester **①** 07955 904884

bruce.belcher@hotmail.co.uk



in linkedin.com/in/belcherbruce



Summary

Senior Professional offering a blend of skills gained from a varied range of experience as a sales executive in a global blue-chip IT company, director of a small business, outdoor pursuits instructor and rowing coach.

Acknowledged as forming trusted relationships with customers and across multiple support teams. Able to identify and negotiate clear, achievable and agreed objectives and work in a team to achieve those objectives. Has a proven track record against sales targets. Provides a structured approach to solving problems and able to synthesise complex issues into clear deliverables.

Skilled as a team leader or enthusiastic participant, motivating and encouraging inclusion and respect between team members. Enjoys competing to win, is persistent and determined.

Experience

Software Developer at Code Nation

May 2019 - August 2019

Code Nation provide training and coaching in software engineering including front and back end coding, web development and application design. Completed a 12 week course to become a Junior Software Developer. The tech stack taught is: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Mongo DB, Express.js and Git.

Research and Administration Officer at Metabolic Support UK

2018 - 2019

Metabolic Support UK are a charity supporting people with rare genetic disorders. Initially provided a wide range of office administrative support, the role developed to include computer infrastructure support and CRM system management and structuring.

Business Development Manager at Aaron & Partners LLP

2016 - 2017

Aaron & Partners LLP solicitors are ranked in the UK top 200 and excel in providing bespoke solutions to complex legal problems. Engaged on a one-year contract to evaluate CRM systems, project manage a major upgrade to the Civica practice management system and be the key point of contact with the Civica account team during this process.

Ward Clerk 2013 - 2015

Provided administrative support to mental health wards on a flexible hour contract basis. Responsible for all non-medical administrative duties on the ward, using CareNotes and NHS Logistics computer systems, working with highly sensitive personal information. Supporting the Nurses and Support Workers in their role looking after the patients and being sensitive to the needs of the patient's friends and family. Required the ability to remain calm in a high stress and potentially hazardous environment.

Voluntary and Community work

2012 - 2013

Applying interpersonal, teaching, organisation and problem-solving skills, with the following organisations:

- Passion for Learning, providing reading support to primary school children from challenging circumstances
- Chester Federation of the Blind, delivering IT training to visually impaired
- Local Community Centre, assisting elderly using IT
- Weaver Housing Trust, mentoring a group of special needs pupils to compete in a Young Enterprise business project
- Grosvenor Rowing Club, setting up an adaptive rowing section

IBM – Various Sales and technical Positions

2000 - 2012

Major Account Sales at IBM

2006 - 2012

Responsible for developing trusted partnerships with IBM's largest clients, delivering contracted business and identifying and closing new business. Organising and consulting with IBM, business and technology partners and customer teams to facilitate the implementation of large, critical projects.

- Consistently over achieved against multi-million dollar sales targets, in last full year, achieved \$18.45 million against target of \$15 million (123%)
- Led sales into major accounts in the finance sector, examples including Legal and General with multiple orders totalling \$4.9 million and QBE returning over \$3million
- Able to establish customer commercial and technical relationships at all levels using expertise in large commercial computer systems technologies
- Received acknowledgements and awards from customers' management and operational staff, business partners and IBM teams, reviewed as a strong and outstanding contributor

Sales Specialist at IBM

2002 - 2006

Hardware sales specialist in the Small and Medium Business sector. Exceeding quotas circa \$5 million by identifying, qualifying and winning new name business and developing partnerships to win additional and repeat business with these customers.

Systems Architect at IBM

2000 - 2002

Designed cross technology IT solutions in collaboration with technical teams from IBM and Business Partners. Presented to all levels including 'C' suite. Rated as an extraordinary contributor.

Director and Instructor, Outdoor Pursuits

1995 - 1999

Set up and managed a small company providing adventure holidays to the leisure, corporate, education and special needs markets, maximum 40 delegates per holiday. The holidays included outdoor pursuits such as walking, climbing and canoeing as well as team building tasks, accommodation, restaurant and bar. Licensed to run the bar.

Account Manager at Sequent Computer Systems

1991 - 1995

Commissioned Account Management and pre-sales Technical Architect. In final year, reported to Partners Director with target of £1 million, achieved 124%. Evaluated as 'outstanding' in my role as Architect.

Influenced IT strategy at senior levels, project managed sales engagements, applied technical expertise to run complex database benchmarking exercises, built trusted relationships with customers through technical consultancy.

Education

University of Hertfordshire

1980 - 1984

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Computer Science 2.1 (Hons)

Liverpool Hope University

2011 - 2012

PGCE, Information Communication Technology